Inventory of the Grayson Neikirk Kefauver papers
Hoover Institution Archives
- Liaison Committee (Folder 23:)
  - Harpers Ferry revisions of "Education for International Security,", 13-18 September 1943 (Folder 23: 3)
  - Meeting agenda, participants, and memorandum, 14 February 1943 (Folder 23: 4)
  - Meeting minutes, January-February 1944 (Folder 23: 5)
  - Meeting, statement of position, January-February 1944 (Folder 23: 6)
  - Meeting agenda, participants, and memorandum, January-February 1944 (Folder 23: 7)
  - Statement to educational press, 26 February 1944 (Folder 23: 8)
- Minutes of Executive Committee meeting, NEA, 23 March 1944 (Folder 23: 9)
- IEA New York meeting, expense accounts for delegates, 12-16 April 1945 (Folder 23: 10)
- IEA, New York meeting, Liaison Committee, invitations and replies, 12-16 April 1945 (Folder 23: 11)
- IEA, New York meeting, invitations and replies, 12-16 April 1945 (Folder 23: 12)
- Liaison Committee (Folder 23)
  - Hood College meeting, 6-9 June 1944 (Folder 23: 13)
  - Meeting agenda, participants, plan of organization, resolutions adopted, 20-21 March 1943 (Folder 24: 1)
  - Meeting, 2 July 1945 (Folder 24: 2)
- IEA, New York meeting, correspondence with Dr. Edgar J. Fisher and Mrs. McCunn, 12-16 April 1945 (Folder 24: 3)
- National Council of Teachers of English, 1943-1945 (Folder 24: 4)
- IEA meeting, 22 November 1944 (Folder 24: 5)
- National Catholic Educational Association, 1943-1945 (Folder 24: 6)
- Liaison Committee meeting, 20-21 November 1944 (Folder 24: 7)
- IEA manuscript for "Education in the United and Associated Nations,", June 1944 (Folder 24: 8)
- Annual report, 1 March 1944-28 February 1945 (Folder 24: 9)
- Informal conference, Coordinating Committee on International Education, 21 March 1943 (Folder 25: 1-3)
- Liaison Committee for International Education, 1944-1945 (Folder 25: 4)
- IEA, 1944-1945 (Folder 25: 5)
- Conference on International Education, Mayflower Hotel, Washington D.C., 14 February 1943 (Folder 25: 6)
- Minutes of Meeting on Reconstruction of Education in Germany, 22 March 1943 (Folder 26: 1)
- Conference of the Liaison Committee for International Education Mayflower Hotel, Washington, D.C., 20-22 May 1943 (Folder 26: 2)
- Liaison Committee for International Education, 5 May 1944 (Folder 26: 3)
- Formation of the Liaison Committee, 1943 (Folder 26: 4)
- National Conference of Christians and Jews, Inc., 1943-1944 (Folder 26: 5)
- Educational and Cultural Organization (ECO), London conference, November 1945 (Folder 26: 6)
- Notes pertaining to the ECO Conference, London, November 1945 (Folder 26: 7)
- General Advisory Committee Division of Cultural Relations minutes, 17-18 September 1941; 23-24 February 1943; 9-10 June 1943; 18-19 February 1944 (Folder 26: 8)
- General Advisory Committee documents, 17-18 September 1941; 23-24 February 1943; 9-10 June 1943; 18-19 February 1944 (Folder 26: 9)
- U.S. Department of State, 1943-1945 (Folder 26: 10)
- Unesco file (Folder 27-31)
  - "Organization des Nations Unies pour l'éducation, la science et la culture: Paris Conference,", June 1946 (Folder 27: 1)
    Majority written in French
  - General Conference, Paris, 1947 (Folder 27: 2-4)
  - U.S. Department of State press release, 1947 (Folder 27: 5)
  - Journal of the General Conference, first session, Paris, 7 December 1946 (Folder 27: 6)
    French and English traslation
  - U.S. Department of State press release, 1943-1946 (Folder 27: 7-10)
  - Prepatory Commission supplementary report on museums, 1946 (Folder 27: 11)
  - Conference for the Establisment of the United Nations Educational, Scientific, and Cultural Organization, London, June 1946 (Folder 28: 1)
  - General Conference, 2 September 1946 (Folder 28: 2)
  - Preparatory Commission Fine Arts Committee, Notice of Meeting, and other materials, 1946 (Folder 28: 3)
  - Preparatory Commission, June 1946 (Folder 28: 4)
  - Preparatory Commission, May 1946 (Folder 28: 5)
  - Prepatory Commission, Executive Committee, circa 1946 (Folder 28: 6)
  - Prepatory Commission, Executive Committee, circa 1946 (Folder 28: 7)
  - Paris Conference, circa 1947 (Folder 29: 1)
  - Paris Conference, circa 1947 (Folder 29: 2)
  - Executive Council, circa 1947 (Folder 29: 3)
  - General Session, Prepatory Commission, circa 1946 (Folder 29: 4)
  - Revised Progress Report on the Program of the United Nations Educational, Scientific, and Cultural Organization, 16 August 1946 (Folder 29: 5)
  - Social Science Committee, 17 July 1946 (Folder 29: 6)
  - Prepatory Commission, Provisional Record, 5 July 1946 (Folder 30: 1)
  - Prepatory Commission, circa 1947 (Folder 30: 2)
  - Prepatory Commission, Technical Sub-Committee, 1945-1946 (Folder 30: 3)
  - Prepatory Commission, Documents, circa 1946 (Folder 30: 4)
  - The School Executive, October 1943 (Folder 31: 1)
- Unesco: Report on Pacific Regional Conference, San Francisco, CA, 13-15 May 1948 (Folder 31: 2)
- The School Executive, March 1944 (Folder 31: 3)
- War and Peace Aims: Extracts from Statements of United Nations Leaders, 30 January 1943 (Folder 31: 4)
- Duplicate of "Conference on International Education held at the Mayflower Hotel, Washington, D.C.,", 14 February 1943 (Folder 31: 5)
- The School Executive, January 1944 (Folder 31: 6)
- Miscellaneous publications, circa 1946 (Folder 31: 7)
- Miscellaneous publications, 1944-1946 (Folder 31: 8)
- School Life, Official Journal of the U.S. Office of Education, December 1946 (Folder 31: 9)
- Miscellaneous correspondence and reports, circa 1945 (Folder 31: 10)
- Unesco file (Folder 31-38)
  - Final Act of Unesco, November 1945 (Folder 31: 11)
  - Miscellaneous publications, 1944-1947 (Folder 31: 12)
  - Miscellaneous publications related to Unesco plans for future schools, circa 1943 (Folder 32: 1)
    Includes Catholic Action, School and Society, and the School Executive
  - Miscellaneous publications related to postwar cooperation, 1944-1948 (Folder 33: 1)
    Includes The Defense of Peace, The Catholic Education Review, Report of the Delegation of the United States of America to the Inter-American Conference on Problems of War and Peace
  - Constitution of the United Nations Educational, Scientific, and Cultural Organization, 16 November 1945 (Folder 33: 2)
  - Miscellaneous publications related to the development of future education systems, 1941-1946 (Folder 34: 1)
    Includes Education for International Security, The ABC of Democracy, Plan for the Stanford Social Education Investigation
  - Department of State Appropriation Bill for 1946 (Folder 34: 2)
  - Worldover Press, 1948 (Folder 34: 3)
    Uncensored reports and articles on international affairs
  - Miscellaneous publications related to socialism and foreign governments, 1943-1947 (Folder 35: 1)
    Includes the report, "National Socialism: Basic Principles, Their Application by the Nazi Party's Foreign Organization, and the Use of Germans Abroad for Nazi Aims"
  - Commission to Study the Organizations of Peace, 1947 (Folder 35: 2)
  - Miscellaneous publications related to postwar education in primary and secondary schools, 1943-1946 (Folder 36: 1)
    Includes Livingstone-The Future of Education, The American Association of University Professors Bulletin, The Report, The School Executive
  - H.R. 2603, 13 March 1945 (Folder 36: 2)
  - London Charter College Presidents and Statements Labor Material Liaison Committee American Council for Education, circa 1944-1945 (Folder 37: 1)
  - American Association for IOE correspondence, 1945 (Folder 37: 2)
  - Extra copies of previous documents, circa 1944 (Folder 37: 3)
  - Department of State material National Convention correspondence and endorsements to Constitution (Unesco) pamphlets, articles, and statements, circa 1949 (Folder 38: 1)
  - Revision and statement of suggestions concerning Unesco; U.S. Convention on Educational Reconstruction, circa 1943 (Folder 38: 2)